http://www.classic-sailing.co.uk/privacy-policy-and-cookies

skippers@classic-sailing.co.uk
HomeOffersView All VoyagesOur VesselsDestinationsInspire MeRYA CoursesOur EthosGalleriesShopNewsContact
Voyage Search
Vessel
Any vesselAnny of CharlestownEuropaEye of the WindIreneJohanna LucretiaMascotteMooskMorgensterOosterscheldeOutdoor GirlPegasusPilgrimRYA Theory CoursesSanta Maria ManuelaTecla
Area
Any sailing area..AntarcticArcticAtlanticAustraliaAzoresBalticBay of BiscayBelgiumBrittanyCanary IslandsCape HornCape VerdeCaribbeanChannel IslandsChileCornwallCubaDenmarkDevonEast CoastEnglish ChannelEuropeFalkland IslesFaroesFinlandFranceGermanyGreece & Greek IslandsGreenland East CoastGreenland West CoastHebridesHollandIcelandIrelandIrish SeaIsles of ScillyLofoten IslandsMadeiraMaine, USAMediterraneanMoroccoNormandyNorth SeaNorth West Passage - Arctic ExpeditionNorwayOceanOrkney IslandsPacificPortugalRussiaScandinaviaScotlandShetland IslesSolentSouth AfricaSouth AmericaSouth GeorgiaSouthern OceanSpainSt KildaSvalbard-SpitsbergenSwedenUKUSAWalesWest Country
Type
Any voyage type..Adventure Voyage 6 days +Art Voyage with ArtistBeginnersBird WatchingCargo Voyages Under SailCoastal Sailing JourneysCoastal WanderingDay SailDelivery tripDesigned for disabled crewDiving Expedition - liveaboardDuke of Edinburgh AwardEvents & FestivalsFamiliesGAP year & Career BreakGift Voucher Trips £99 - £399Island HoppingKayaking and SailingLearn to sail a gaff rigged vesselLearn to sail a luggerLearn to sail square rigMusic and Sailing with musicianNorthern Lights SpottingOcean passagePhotography Voyage with expertpractical navigation & pilotageRYA Competent CrewRYA Day SkipperRYA Practical Courses at SeaRYA Theory Courses - onlineRYA Yachtmaster Prep & ExamShort Breaks and Tasterssmall boat skillsTall Ship VoyageTall Ships RaceTrans Atlantic CrossingTravel the WorldTry Astro Nav at SeaWatch Leader TrainingWeekend VoyagesWildlifeWinter SunYouth Only Voyage
From date
Voyage No.
Privacy Policy and Cookies
Privacy. Cookie and Delivery Policies
Privacy Policy
At Classic Sailing LTD, we are committed to protecting and respecting your privacy.
When you provide us with any information, it will be handled and processed by one of the five Classic Sailing staff. If you want to learn more about who we are, check out our contact us page for more information.
When you apply for a voyage with Classic Sailing your information will be passed onto the relevant ship's office to check your application and for safety, security and health purposes for your voyage. All sailing partners of Classic Sailing have signed a GDPR data sharing agreement which sets out conditions to abide by when handling your personal information. This agreement is complicit with GDPR and ensures that your information is handled responsibly and lawfully.
Privacy Policy to Print or Download pdf.
This policy explains when and why we ask for your personal information, how we use it, the conditions under which we may disclose it to others and how we keep it secure.
We only use the information we collect about you carefully, lawfully and in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998 and the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)
Classic Sailing is always striving to provide the best service for you, we have created our own Customer Charter which sets out our promise to you.
Read our Classic Sailing Customer Charter Promise here.
Classic Sailing LTD is both your data controller and processor with regards to your personal information.
Who are we?
Classic Sailing Ltd is a Limited UK Company (Reg no. 3256249)
Registered Trademark under Trade Mark number: UK00003204653.
Established in 1996, we have been operating for over 20 years.
The registered address is Classic Sailing Ltd, Mermaids, St Mawes, TR2 5AA.
You can contact us by email at skippers@classic-sailing.co.uk
By Post at our office address:
Classic Sailing, Parton Vrane, Portscatho, Cornwall TR2 5ET
Or by phone during office hours: +44 (0)1872 580022
What information do we collect from you?
We collect personal identifiable information from you such as a name and email address for our e-newsletter.
For Booking
When you apply for a voyage, Classic Sailing will need to assess your suitability for the trip before confirming your booking place to ensure your health and safety.
We do not collect personally identifiable information from children under the age of 18 years unless it has been provided by the parent or legal guardian for the purposes of joining one of our vessels for a voyage.
Completing a Voyage Application Form on behalf of another individual.
If you are completing a booking on behalf of another person (Third party personal and sensitive data) you confirm that they consent to the processing of their personal data and that you have informed them of our identity and the purposes for which the data will be processed.
For Incomplete Booking Forms
When you save your booking form to complete later, Classic Sailing will receive a copy and may get in touch to see if we can help, or reserve you a place.
Sensitive Data
We are required to collect the relevant sensitive data about you for the purposes of the contract (booking a voyage). If you do not provide us with this information when applying for your voyage, it may mean we will not be able to proceed with your booking.
We may need some or all of the following information depending on the type of trip you are wishing to book in order to fulfil the contract or service of the product you have booked.
Personal contact information to communicate with you about your trip by email, phone or by post.
Date of birth – to ensure the trip you have booked is appropriate for your age
Dietary requirements – to help the ship’s cook provide for your needs!
Emergency contact or next of kin contact details –to get in touch with someone ashore in case of an emergency during your voyage.
Any pertinent medical information and details of any prescribed medication with dosage – in case you need medical attention during your trip.
Form of appropriate identification relevant to the trip you have booked. This might include either your passport information, driving license or identity card.
Depending on your answers to the medical questions on our booking form, Classic Sailing LTD may require an additional medical form or letter from your doctor. These medical forms or letters will be sent securely and confidentiality will be paramount in how we handle this information.
For Payments:
Classic Sailing does not hold credit card information. Stripe, a third party PCI compliant payment processor, handles all interactions with credit card information on our behalf. If you pay over the phone, then the card details will be entered directly by one of our team into the Stripe card processor and will never be stored elsewhere by Classic Sailing or Stripe.
How we collect your personal information
You can provide us with the personal and sensitive information we need through a variety of different methods including:
Directly through our website by completing a form, this could be for booking voyages, sending voyage feedback, subscribing to our mailing list, entering a competition, survey or promotion.
Our website is https secure and the web form is encrypted to prevent anyone apart from Classic Sailing using your information.
By email or over the phone.
Through our secure online webchat service
You are always welcome to ring us in the office and provide us with the information over the phone, we will then email you within one working day with links to our terms and conditions and privacy policy for you to access.  01872 58 00 22
Why we need it
We require the personal and sometimes sensitive information in order to process your booking and confirm your voyage reservation.
The Captain or Skipper is responsible for your safety during your trip, accuracy of this information is therefore of high importance.
We do not collect any personal information which we do not need, any of the details which we collect will be relevant for the voyage you are booking.
How we use this information
Marketing Communication.
You will receive marketing communication from us if you have:
Requested information from us or purchased a voyage, gift voucher, or product from us.
If you have subscribed to our e-newsletters and ticked the box to consent.
In both instances, not opted out of receiving that marketing.
-Name and Email Address-
When you subscribe to our Classic Sailing LTD email newsletters and given us consent to do so, we will collect your name and email address for the purposes of sending you our regular news letters, stories, latest offers, competitions and new voyages or destinations.
Your email address will never be passed on to anyone else and you can unsubscribe at any time.
Additionally, your email address and name may be provided to us by someone you know when they ask us to send you further information about a voyage we offer, or if someone has purchased a gift voucher on your behalf. This does not give us permission to subscribe you to our marketing emails. Subscribe links can be found in all our correspondence to you and in the footer of our website.
We also collect your name and email address when you contact us for information, such as through email or our online web chat service, this does not give us permission to subscribe you to our marketing emails. Subscribe links can be found in all of our correspondence to you and in the footer of our website.Personal and Sensitive Information
The personal information we collect will be processed by one of the four trained full-time office staff, located in Cornwall, UK.
Classic Sailing will use the personal information provided to assess your suitability for the voyage you have applied to sail on.
Classic Sailing LTD will not share this information with any who is not authorised by you as outlined below.
By applying for a voyage and upon receipt of your payment confirmation, you agree to Classic Sailing securely sharing your personal information to the vessel operator or owner for the sole purpose of the contract/your booking.
Our partners have or will have by May 25th 2018 agreed to the same level of privacy protections and are committed to handling your information securely, carefully and lawfully.
The operator or owner may make contact with you directly for reasons relating directly to your voyage.
The Captain or Skipper for the voyage you have booked is responsible for your safety during your trip and will safely and securely store your personal information.
How long we keep it for
We always ensure that your personal and sensitive information is kept secure and only kept for as long as necessary for the purpose for which they are used.
If your details change before a voyage, please either edit your booking form online or email us at skippers@classic-sailing.co.uk
We will always update your personal information promptly and inform you of the changes made by you in writing.
We will retain your information for as long as needed to provide you with the services. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.
It is company policy to retain details of the voyage you booked and certain personal data for 7 years from the date the voyage ends.
Your rights
You are always entitled to ask for a copy of any information we hold about you. If you wish to have a copy, please email us at skippers@classic-sailing.co.uk
You can always opt out of emails or request deletion of your information from our system at any time;
You can opt out of marketing emails by clicking the unsubscribe link included in every email. This will opt you out of receiving our e-newsletter, but not relating to a specific product/voyage/service you have booked.
To request deletion of all your personal information from our system, please email skippers@classic-sailing.co.uk to be removed. If we will need to retain the information to provide you with a service you have booked or to comply with legal obligations, then we will inform you of the process.
Third Party Websites
We cannot guarantee the security of any third-party website which we link on the Classic Sailing website, it is your responsibility to check their own privacy policies and cookie policy.
Authorised Third Parties
We use third party systems to assist us in processing your personal information, we require these third parties to comply with our privacy policy and any other appropriate confidentiality and security measures.
Third party systems such as payment processors, marketing campaign providers, web chat services, database system and web forms on our website are all examples of where we will use third parties to process your information.
Each and every third party processor we utilise has been checked for security and data processing agreements for each one have been signed.
Security and Cookies
We will notify you immediately if there was a breach of your personal information.
Cookies are used to collect information about how visitors use our site. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the site from and the pages they visited.
Google’s Privacy policy relating to these Cookies is available here: http://www.google.com/analytics/learn/privacy.html
To opt out of being tracked by Google Analytics across all websites visit http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout
Cookies are used on our web site. You can disable this by not allowing cookies when you view our web pages.
Classic Sailing uses Google Tracking Code and Facebook Pixel Code to monitor the usage of our web pages.
We use cookies to operate our Chat Service which is provided by Olark.com
Delivery Policy
Your voyage start dates are when you purchase is considered delivered. The voyage is confirmed to you on your first or only payment for the voyage.
Anti-Social Behaviour Privacy Notice
This Anti-Social Behaviour Privacy Notice works in conjunction with Classic Sailing’s Privacy Notice
Everything we do with information about our customers or prospects has to comply with Data Protection Act and the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) that came into force in May 2018.
If anything in this notice is not clear, if you have further queries, or to make a complaint please get in contact Classic Sailing on 01872 580022 or via email skippers@classic-sailing.co.uk.
Why Classic Sailing needs information about you
Classic Sailing collects information about you to address complaints of anti-social behaviour.
Classic Sailing has a legal basis for processing and collecting your information under Article 6 GDPR, the Anti-social Behaviour Crime and Policing Act 2014.
The processing is necessary for this reason:
Zero Tolerance for abuse of other guests and professional crew.
The processing is necessary for Classic Sailing to ensure sailors and professional crew are not put into jeopardy or suffer any form of abuse by anti-social behaviour of other sailors or professional crew due to the close proximity of living, eating and sleeping on a tall ship or traditional sailing vessel.
What do we use your information for
Personal information that you supply to us may be used in a number of ways, for example:
Record, investigate and resolve complaints of anti-social behaviour for safety and well being purposes and for audit for statistical analysis.
We will share, as appropriate, your information with other services, voyage suppliers and agencies we work with for information about you. This information will help us deal with your case quickly.
Other services and agencies will include, voyage suppliers, the Police, Probation Service, or the Home Office.
How long we keep hold of information for
Your information will be kept safe and confidential and handled with care in accordance with the law.
Classic Sailing will keep your information for a maximum of seven years.
We will only use your information within the terms of data protection laws, and will delete your information securely and only keep it for as long as necessary.  Classic Sailing will review dates for keeping personal data in the future and if necessary update this Privacy Notice.
If you are unhappy with any aspect of how your information has been collected and/or used, you can make a complaint to Classic Sailing Directors.  You can also report concerns to the national regulator, the Information Commissioner’s Office.  Their details can be found on their website:
https://ico.org.uk/concerns/handling/
Data Protection Officer Contact Details
Email: data.protection@milton-keynes.gov.uk
Tel. No: 01908 254767
Date Published: May 15th 2018
Our Privacy Policy has been developed to strictly conform the General Data Protection Regulations, these regulations have not yet been completely explained by the Government and we have interpreted them to the best of our abilities.
From time to time we may change this policy, it is your responsibility to check this page occasionally to ensure that you’re happy with any changes. We will of course contact you with any materially significant alteration.
Any questions regarding this policy and our privacy practices should be sent by email to
skippers@classic-sailing.co.uk
or by writing to
Classic Sailing LTD, Parton Vrane, Portscatho, Cornwall TR2 5ET.
Alternatively, you can telephone on +44 (0)1872 580022.
Classic Sailing Ltd,
Registered address, Mermaids, St Mawes, Cornwall TR2 5AA
Trading address, Parton Vrane, Portscatho, Cornwall TR2 5ET
www.classic-sailing.co.uk
01872 58 00 22
REG NO: 3256249.
VAT NO: GB794981950.
What others say about us
CURRENT AVERAGE   4.6 STARS
249 REVIEWS
Facebook reviews
"A life changing experience with talented crew who gave us hope for mankind ...and biscuits"
Customer comments
Read what the press say about our holidays
Magazine articles
Why book with Classic Sailing?
The call of the sea
Destinations for sailors & explorers
Over 300 voyages a year
11, 051 customers introduced to
traditional boats and tall ships.
Registered Address: Classic Sailing Ltd, Mermaids, St Mawes, TR2 5AA.
REG NO: 03256249. VAT NO: 794 981950
Newsletter & Offers
Be social
